《比利小子》前情提要
Previously on Billy the Kid...
行走西部是件危险的事 比利
Travelin'west is a dangerous business, Billy.
结局并不总是如我们所愿
Things don't always end up the way we want'em to.
比利
－ Billy!
这不是玩具
This is not a toy.
如果你不打算开枪 就别拿它指着人
You never point that at a man unless you intend to use it.
你想做什么 比利
What is it you want to be, Billy?
你已经是亡命之徒了 孩子
You're an outlaw now, boy.
你没什么选择了
- You ain't got a lot of options. -
我还是想改邪归正 杰西
I still have a hankerin' to go straight, Jesse.
这怎么可能呢 两个县都在通缉你
How's that gonna happen? You're wanted in two counties.
你已经出名了
You're gettin' pretty famous now.
你的脸被贴的到处都是 你的事迹口口相传
Your face is all over the place. People talk about you.
我不在乎 我只知道
That don't mean nothing to me. I sure as hell
我不想因为杀人而出名
don't wanna be famous for killing people.
托巴斯克小姐
Senorita Del Tobosco.
我是想自我介绍一下
I just wanted to introduce myself.
你以为我对这镇上的事一无所知吗
Do you imagine I had no idea of what happens in this town?
真为你汗颜
Shame on you.
有个人墨菲 他在林肯开了家大商店
This guy Murphy- - he owns a big store in Lincoln.
他们成立了一家名为浩世的公司
They got a company called The House,
就通过墨菲的店经营
and they run it outta Murphy's store.
比利 我很荣幸
Well, Billy, I want to say it's a great honor
终于见到你本人了 真是蓬荜生辉
to finally meet you in the flesh. Great honor.
这是我的合伙人 约翰尼·莱利吉姆·多兰
My partners here- Johnny Riley, Jim Dolan.
这是我的王国 要真被英国混蛋夺走
This is my kingdom. I'll be damned if I'm gonna let
我也就无颜活在世上了
some prick Englishmen take it away from me.
你也许见过街那头的那家新店
You may have seen this new store down at the end of the street.
你到底在干什么
What the hell are you doin'?
别跟我耍心眼儿 小子
Don't get smart with me, boy.
嘿 我们结束了
Hey, we're done here.
没有人可以先跟我断交 没有人
No one...is gonna foreclose on us. No one.
你在威胁我们 你要是真想威胁的话
You threathenin' us? Cause if you are.
也没人能打败我们
And no one is gonna outgun us.
我早劝你 别把粮食卖给汤斯顿
I told you not to sell grain to Tunstall, all right?
你我有协议在先
You have a contract with us.
我是说 战争正在酝酿
I'm talkin' about the war that's brewin',
墨菲和汤斯顿之间的战争
the war between Murphy and Tunstall.
墨菲显然更有钱
· Murphy's got the loudest pocket.
比利 这些人 啥玩意儿也不是
Billy, these people, they don't mean anything.
我同意和汤斯顿见面
I agree to meet with Tunstall.
但必须秘密见面
It has to be in secret.
这就是你等待一生的
This is the time and place
那个时刻 那个地点
you have waited for all your life.
我不再为墨菲少校干活了
I'm quittin'Major Murphy's payroll.
我从英国人汤斯顿那里接了份工作
I accepted a job with the Englishmen, Tunstall.
你真以为我们会这么放了你
Do you really think we're just gonna let you leave?
让他走他吧 会有我们收拾他的时候
Let him go his way. Our time will come.
是啊 会的
Yeah, it will.
好了 我们走 快走
Okay, let's go. Let's go!
晚上回来救你俩 好吗
You two, you're up next, all right?
翻过墙你就安全了 好吧
Over the wall and you're safe. Okay?
比利 我做不到
－ Billy, I can't.
这是唯一的出路 好吗查理 准备好了吗
This is the only way, all right? Charlie. You ready?
快走 快快快
Go, go, go. Go, go, go!
妈的
Fuck!
这帮混蛋
You fuckers!
强尼 桌子
Johnny. Table!
强尼 我们得走了 走吧 来
Johnny, we gotta go! We gotta go. Come on!
准备好了吗3 2 1
You ready? 3...2...1.
先生们 我相信大家都知道我们来这儿的原因
Gentlemen, I believe we all know why we're here.
事实很明确 我们已经跟
There is no hiding the fact that we are now effectively
与墨菲先生和浩世公司开战了
at war with Mr. Murphy and the House.
我听说墨菲在扩充军队
I hear Murphy's hiring more guns.
我知道 我也在招兵买马
I know, but I've been recruiting, too.
我想你们已经认识
I think you gentlemen have already made the acquaintance
弗雷德·怀特和约翰·米德尔顿了
of Fred Waite and John Middleton.
对 我们基本上都认识
Yeah. We mostly all know each other.
大多数人也知道胡安·佩特龙
And most of you will also know Juan Patron,
他是西裔社区的主要成员
as a leading member of the Hispanic community.
他是个重要成员 因为他能说服社区
He's very important because he can persuade that community
信任并支持我们
to trust and support us.
我向各位保证
Now, I promise you
我最不想看到枪火四起
the last thing I want is a shooting match.
但如果真到了那一天 我们必须做好准备
But if it comes to it, we have to be ready.
另外告诉大家 我要任命比利
I want you all to know that I'm appointing Billy
作为我的副手
as my second- in- command.
我不在时 大家听他的号令
So, if I'm not around, you'll take your orders from him.
谢谢您的好意 汤斯顿先生
I thank you for your gesture, Mr. Tunstall.
但我认为这个职位应该交给迪克·布鲁尔
But I think you should give the job to Dick Brewer.
当然 既然你真这么想我就同意了
Of course. If that is your wish, Billy, I concur.
好了 大家明确一下前进的方向
So, let's be clear about the way forward.
我不会被墨菲和他的爪牙吓到
I will not be intimidated by Murphy and his crooks.
恰恰相反 这让我进一步放手发展事业
On the contrary, I intend to pursue my business freely- -
我会扩大商店
expanding my store,
增加牲畜 甚至开一家新银行
my cattle stock, and even opening a new bank- -
为林肯人民提供更便捷的贷款
a bank that will offer the people of Lincoln
逃离浩世公司
easy credit and a way of escaping
腐败的商业剥削
- the House's corrupt business practices. -
不是我扫大家的兴 汤斯顿先生
I don't want to be the fly in the ointment, Mr. Tunstall.
但我得提醒一下 墨菲家族颇有些有权有势的朋友
But I must remind the meeting that Murphy still has powerful friends.
我们不仅是在挑战浩世公司
We're not just taking on the House here.
也是在挑战圣达菲圈
We're also taking on the Santa Fe Ring,
这下性质就完全不一样了
and that is a different proposition altogether.
我真的很感激您的提议 汤斯顿先生
You know, I really did appreciate the offer, Mr. Tunstall.
但布鲁尔比我来的时间更长
But Brewer's been here longer.
他了解您的运营方式 手下也信任他
He knows your operation, and the men trust him.
你支持他 我自然也会支持他
Well, if he has your support, he'll certainly have mine.
知道吗 小子们
You know, boys...
杰西·埃文斯屠杀那家农户
… maybe Jesse Evans went too far,
连孩子都不放过 可能有点太过分了
killing those farmers, even their children.
把我的名声和生意拖下了水 对吧
Dragging my name and my business through the mud, eh?
汤斯顿是想从内部分裂我们
Tunstall is trying to break us.
妈的
Shit.
听我说
Listen to me.
我打个响指就能毁掉汤斯顿
I can ruin Tunstall just like that.
所有想破坏我生意的人 都是一样下场
Same way I ruined anybody else who tried to muscle in on my business.
这不光是你的生意了
It's no longer your business.
我们买了你的股份记得吗现在是我们的生意
We bought you out, remember? And right now, our business
濒临破产
is staring bankruptcy right in the face.
我们要对付的不只是汤斯顿和几个当地农户
We're not just dealing with Tunstall and a few local farmers.
他已把比利小子招致麾下
He has Billy the Kid working for him.
那又怎样 你不们明白 我又不想打仗
So? You don't get it. I don't want a war.
你没有选择 我们得到消息
You don't have a choice. We have information that
汤斯顿想在本地开银行
Tunstall wants to open up a bank here.
我们最大的债主 托马斯·卡特伦
Our biggest lender, Thomas Catron, who just happens
也就是卡特伦银行和信托的总裁
to be the President of Catron Bank and Trust,
绝对不希望看到这一幕
isn't exactly gonna like that.
我知道卡特伦是谁
I know who Catron is.
我得提醒你 我和卡特伦先生
Need I remind ya's that Mr. Catron and I
是老朋友了 我们仍然一起做生意
are old friends and that we still do business together.
卡特伦会对付那个银行的
Catron will deal with the bank.
-即便如此  -天
Even so- - - Jesus!
你们真是俩开心果啊
So, the two of you make me laugh.
真他妈让我发笑
You make me fuckin' laugh.
你们开玩笑呢吧
Are you kiddin'me?
你真的认为他们会在林肯
Do you really think that they're going to open up
开银行吗 真的吗 为谁而开
a bank here in Lincoln? Really? Who for?
这里大多数人是墨西哥 而且穷得要命
Most of them are Mexicans and piss poor, for Christ's sakes!
我倒要问问 他们要银行干什么
What in the name of God do they need a bank for?
能告诉我吗 嗯
Will you tell me that, eh?
管好那个杰西·埃文斯
Keep Jesse Evans on a leash.
都下去吧
We're done here.
你愿意和我一起出来 我很开心
I'm glad you wanted to ride out with me.
你为啥觉得我不会 就因为你是逃犯
Why did you think I wouldn't? Because you're an outlaw?
也许吧
Maybe.
虽然我已经不是了
Although I'm not anymore.
汤斯顿先生帮我处理好了
Mr. Tunstall saw to that.
那是好事啊 比利
I'm so happy to hear that, Billy.
是吗
Yeah?
你父母呢 他们也会觉得是好事吗
What about your parents? Will they be happy?
我们家族依然深受西班牙裔影响
My family still has a strong Spanish heritage.
他们的观念更传统一点
They are tied to the old ways.
那你自己呢
And yourself?
我认为还是应该是适应新生活方式
I think it's better to adapt to this new way of life.
毕竟我们也改变不了 但他们不同意
We can't change it, but they don't agree.
过去对他们来说太重要
The past is so important to them.
我听到了些传闻
I hear things,
我担心 如果谣言属实
and I'm scared that if the rumors are true,
我们可能被卷入这两大商行的斗争
we may all be dragged into war between these two shopkeepers.
你不会有事的
Nothing will happen to you.
我保证
Promise.
不如你我回马厩看看
Why don't you come back and see the stables with me?
你父母呢
What about your parents?
他们不在家
They're not home.
-谢谢   -谢谢
- Gracias. - Gracias.
你说的是西班牙语
- It's Spanish.
安达卢西亚马
An Andalusian horse.
我亲自训练的他
I broke and trained him myself.
谢谢
Gracias.
过来
Ven.
真棒
Bonita.
过来 来
Ven. Vamos.
很好
Muy bien.
对了
Eso.
好神奇
Amazing.
谢
Thank you. -
杰西
Jesse.
等等 等等
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
先生们
Gentlemen.
我们还没互相认识过
I don't think we've, uh, been introduced.
这位是巴克赛特·罗伯茨
This here is Buckshot Roberts.
他是我们的人了 一个神枪手
He's joined us. He's an amazing sharpshooter.
很高兴见到你 罗伯茨先生
Well, it's a pleasure to meet you, Mr. Roberts.
你有什么要告诉我们的吗
You have something to tell us?
我们跟墨菲先生聊过了
We met with Mr. Murphy.
他觉得自己做得过分了
He thinks he might have gone a little bit far,
他不想和汤斯顿开战
and he doesn't want to wage a war with Tunstall.
这老醉鬼真他妈宅心仁厚啊 上帝保佑
Seems the old drunk's got a tender conscience, God help him.
你觉得呢
What did you say?
拜托 明眼人都知道我们已经开战了
Come on, we all know that we're already at war.
我调查汤斯顿的生意好久了
I've been checking out Tunstall's operation,
我知道他把牛马养在什么地方
and I know where he keeps most of his cattle and his horses.
要是我们开战 搞个突然袭击如何
If we're going to war, what say we raid'em?
突袭
Raid'em?
那么好吧
Good then.
我们同意
We're agreed.
但要先等等
But hang fire for a little while.
别给汤斯顿留下诉诸法律的机会
We don't want to give Tunstall any excuses to go to the law.
那我们在这里干嘛
Then what the fuck are we doin'here?
埃文斯先生 你们在这里
Well, what you're doing here, Mr. Evans.
要盯着你朋友比利小子
...is you're gonna keep an eye on your friend,
因为他是我们所有人的威胁
Billy the Boy, cause he's a danger to all of us.
别担心 埃文斯先生
Don't you worry, Mr. Evans.
有你过瘾的时候
You'll get your excitement.
查理 你知道跟浩世公司的生意
Charlie, you know this business with the House
最后会很难收场 对吧
might get messy, right?
你老婆刚怀了第一个孩子 你输不起的
With your wife carryin' your first child and all, you got a lot to lose.
我不能一走了之
I can't walk away.
不能在这个时候
Not now.
来吧 好姑娘
Come on, girl. Attagirl.
过来 女孩 来吧
Here, girl. Come on.
如果你死了
If you get killed...
我该对这个遗腹子说些什么
… what do I tell the child who will never meet their father?
你终于像个战士了 查理
You look like a soldier now, Charlie.
这很奇怪 比利 但我觉得我早就认识你了
It's...it's strange, Billy, but I...I feel like I know you already.
当然 我知道这不可能
Of course, I don't, really.
-说说你自己吧  -你想听什么
Tell me something about yourself. - What is there to know?
跟我说说你的家庭吧
Well, tell me about your family.
我家里有母亲 父亲 我哥哥乔
I had a mother, a father, little brother Joe.
他们都死了
They all died.
我在英国有三个姐妹
I have three sisters.
她们对我来说
back home in England, and.
就是整个世界
they all mean the world to me.
我妈妈这个人很特别
My mom was a very special person.
她眼中的世界与大多数人不同
Saw the world different to most.
只是没能活下去
Just didn't make it.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
没必要抱歉
No need to be sorry.
你给了我机会 让我过上了已经不再奢望的生活
You've given me a chance at a life I'd almost stopped believing in.
你必须相信 比利 你必须保持信念
Well, you must believe in it, Billy, you must.
每个人都值得第二次机会
Everyone deserves a second chance.
但我知道你为了投奔我 放弃了很多
But I- - I know you gave up a lot to join me.
你的那些朋友
You had friends?
杰西 当然
Jesse, sure.
我跟他交情很深
Jesse and I go a long way back.
他总喜欢游走在法律之外
He always liked living outside the law.
我不喜欢
I don't.
所以我才来投奔你的
That's why I'm here.
先生们
Gentlemen.
晚上好
Good evening.
请允许我自我介绍下
Allow me to introduce myself.
我叫埃德加·华尔兹
My name is Edgar Walz.
我是托马斯·卡特伦先生的女婿
I am the son- in- law of Mr. Thomas Catron,
也是他的经纪人
as well as his agent.
那么 我想你们应该就是
Now, I presume you are.
多兰先生和莱利先生了
Mr. Dolan and Mr. Riley?
的确 华尔兹先生 我是约翰尼·莱利
Indeed, Mr. Walz. Johnnie Riley,
很荣幸见到你
and it is our absolute pleasure to meet you.
我是吉姆·多兰
And I'm Jim Dolan.
很高兴你来这一趟 华尔兹先生
We're glad you could make it, Mr. Walz.
你快坐 我倒酒
You sit. I'll pour.
当然乐意
By all means.
我们应该为浩世的成功干一杯
I think we should drink to the success of the House, no?
为什么布呢
Yes. Why not?
我是代表卡特伦先生 来这里办要事的
I am here on important business on behalf of Mr. Catron.
卡特伦对浩世公司
Mr. Catron is deeply concerned
目前的财政状况此深表关切
about the current financial position of the House,
他想知道背后的负责人究竟是谁
and he's actually wondering who the hell is running this show?
因为他知道墨菲先生似乎
Because he knows that Mr. Murphy is somewhat.
有点无能
－… incapacitated.
但说实话 他对你俩小丑的期望更高
But to be honest, he expected more from you two jokers.
这么说似乎有点不公平吧 华尔兹先生
That seems a little bit unfair, doesn't it, Mr. Walz?
这是生意 多兰先生
It's business, Mr. Dolan.
生意为大
It's business.
我们和卡特伦先生有同样的担忧
We share Mr. Catron's concerns.
我们知道浩世在赔钱
We know that the House is losing money,
我们还知道英国人汤斯顿
and we know the Englishman Tunstall
正在跟我们争夺市场
is comin' to some of our markets.
他还开了一家银行
He's also opened a bank.
一家该死的银行 就在你们眼皮底下
A fucking bank, right under your noses.
卡特伦先生对此完全不能接受
Now, that is totally unacceptable to Mr. Catron.
你俩要是坐以待毙
And if you two don't do something
任由这个英国人开商店
about closing that bank, and stop this Englishman
开银行的话
from running his store.
卡特伦先生别无选择
Mr. Catron has no other option
只能把两位剔除利益集团了
than to remove you two gentlemen from the equation.
明白吗
You got that?
太好了
Wonderful.
祝二位有个愉快的夜晚
I wish you two a very pleasant evening.
好球
Shot.
算他走运
He got lucky.
我们有话要对你说
We've got something to say to you.
是吗
Yeah?
是的
Yeah.
我们认为 该由我们完全
We've decided that it's time to take over
接受这里的生意了
runnin'the business ourselves entirely.
你知道 我们买下浩世时
You see, when we acquired the House,
你告诉我们你打算退休
you told us you were planning to retire
去圣达菲悠闹养老
and live a nice, comfortable life in Santa Fe.
我说过吗
Did I say that?
当然
Aye.
是的
Yeah.
我还没准备好退休
Well, I ain't ready to retire.
我们认为你应该退休
We think you ought to.
那你们就想错了 不是吗
Well, then, that's your mistake. Isn't it?
咱们继续比赛吧
Let's get on with the game, shall we?
不 我们受够了 这一切该结束了
No. We're gettin tired of this, and it's got to end.
劳伦斯 我们不是请你退休
See, Lawrence, we're not asking ya to retire.
是通知你退休
We're telling ya.
你要真觉得我会把生意交给你们俩 趁早滚蛋
You can fuck off if you think I'm gonna leave my business over to you two.
两个操蛋的骗子 对做生意一窍不通
Pair of fuckin' hustlers. You don't know jack shit
他妈的永远也学不会
about runnin' a business, and you never fuckin'will.
而你呢 是个没用又可悲的酒鬼
And you are a useless and pathetic drunk.
让自己和公司蒙羞
You're an embarrassment to yourself and to this business.
没有我 你们什么都不是
And you're fuckin nothin' without me.
一文不值
Fuckin'nothin'.
来啊
Go on.
开枪啊
Pull the trigger.
你最好点种 墨菲
You better play bold, Murphy.
已经变天了
Things have changed.
你永远不知道下一个会是谁
You never know who could be next.
很高兴大家都到了
It's good to have you all here with us.
能请到萨图尼诺·巴卡先生 还有他的
It's particularly gratifying to have Mr. Saturnino Baca here
两个漂亮的女儿 我十分荣幸
and his two beautiful daughters.
萨图尼诺一直是浩世的大力支持者
Saturnino has been a great supporter of the House
多年以来 他为我们带来了
for many years, and he has brought with him
许多墨西哥朋友和友邻
into the fold many of our Mexican friends and neighbors.
但我们这次请你过来
But one of the reasons that we did want you
是为了在我合伙人 大家的朋友
here with us is to, uh, reassure you
吉姆·多兰惨死之后
as to the future of the House,
让大家对浩世的未来
after the tragic demise of my partner
仍旧保持信心
and our friend Jim Dolan.
吉姆是个好人 我们会怀念他
Jim was a good man. He will be missed.
但你大可以放心 我们的生意欣欣向荣
But you may be rest assured that our business is in good hands.
我们有托马斯·卡特伦先生的资金支持
We have the financial backing of Mr. Thomas Catron,
他恰好是新墨西哥最有权势的人
who happens to be the single most powerful individual in New Mexico.
我们将携手一起应对
And together, we will deal with the threat
英国人汤斯顿的威胁
of the Englishman, Tunstall.
这个人会很快成为历史 我向您保证
The man will soon be history. You have my word.
因此 选择我们 您的和生命和未来才有保障
That's why your future and lives are safe with us.
享用吧
Enjoy.
杰西
Jesse.
我听说汤斯顿要去拉斯维加斯
I have heard that Tunstall is going to Las Vegas,
这是你和你的部下破坏他生意的
so it might be a good time for you and some of your boys
好时机
to damage his interests.
这里我们说了算 不是他
We run things here, not him.
我知道汤斯顿有些牲畜养在
I know Tunstall keeps some of his stock
迪克·布鲁尔在鲁伊多索的农场
down at Dick Brewer's ranch down on the Ruidoso.
我允许你去捣毁他的牲畜
Then you have my permission to fuck with his herd.
你没事吧
You all right?
想和我一起来吗
You want to come with me?
去找点乐子
Go have some fun?
来吧
Come on, then.
你得闭上眼睛
You gotta close your eyes.
-安娜  -爸爸
- Ana! - Papa!
你侵犯了我的女儿 外国佬
You violate my daughter, gringo.
-就要付出代价  -把枪放下 老家伙
- You pay. - Put that down, old man.
我没对你女儿做什么
I didn't do anything to your daughter.
嘿 这里到底是怎么回事
Hey. What the fuck's goin on here?
杰西 别开枪
Jesse, don't shoot him!
萨图尼诺 把枪放下
Saturnino, put down the gun.
朋友 你雇佣歹徒
This is what happens, my friend,
就会是这个结果 一帮禽兽
when you employ gangsters, los criminales.
把枪放下 为了你好 朋友
For your own sake, amigo, put down the gun.
很好 这对了
Now. That's it.
别再用枪指着我了 墨西哥人
Don't ever point your gun at me again, Mexican,
下次你就死定了
or you're a dead man.
只要我愿意 别说你女儿
If I want, I'll have my way, not just with your daughter,
整个世界都任我鱼肉
but I'll have my way...with the whole world.
这就是我
That's who I am.
我 我只想说 在我看来
I, I just wanted to say that the recent...suicide
吉姆·多兰最近的自杀
of Jim Dolan seems to me to be a sure sign
恰恰是浩世财务混乱的表现
that the House is now in financial turmoil.
那么 就请麦克斯文先生
And...Well, I'll let Mr. McSween
跟大家说说 我们最新的法律进展
tell you about our latest Iegal developments.
针对粮食和牲畜的极低定价
The fixing of low prices for grain and cattle
使许多农民陷入贫困
has reduced many of the farmers to penury.
我们代表这些农户 正在发起一场
On behalf of those farmers, we are instigating
对浩世的法律诉讼
legal proceedings against the House.
多亏了老威尔逊法官
And thanks to old Judge Wilson,
我被任命为副警长
I've been appointed Deputy Sheriff,
尽管布雷迪警长表示反对
despite the objections of Sheriff Brady.
你知道吗 我越来越相信
You know what? I'm really startin' to believe
汤斯顿可以赢了
that Tunstall can win this thing.
我也是
Me, too.
你说呢 比利
What say you, Billy?
讲真吗
Honestly?
如果真要发生枪战
If it comes to a shooting war,
优势在另一方
the other side has the advantage.
你们只是农民
You're farmers.
杰西·埃文斯和他的部下都是职业杀手
Jesse Evans and his gang are all practiced killers.
他们不会把我们放在眼里的
They got to be thinking we're easy meat.
没想到你会说这种丧气话
That's not exactly what I wanted to hear comin'from you.
拜托 乔治 你不能逃避事实
Come on, George, you can't hide from the truth.
但还有另一个事实
But there's another truth.
普通人也能做出不平凡的事
Ordinary folk can perform extraordinary deeds,
尤其在有信仰加持时
especially if they believe in something,
我相信汤斯顿
and I believe in Tunstall.
我相信他跟墨菲和达菲圈开战
I believe he's doing the right thing
是在行正义之事
fighting Murphy and the Rings.
我会为他的事业而战
And I will fight for his cause.
比利 能私下聊聊吗
Uh, Billy, can I have a word?
我想跟你说件事
There was just, uh, one other thing I wanted to say.
杰西·埃文斯对我们威胁极大
Jesse Evans is a real danger to us.
你有没有可能说服他
Is there any way, perhaps, that you can persuade him
别为墨菲做事了
not to work for Murphy?
考虑一下吧
Just...think about it.
谢谢
Thank you.
查理
Whoa, Charlie.
没事的
I think it's okay.
小朋友 过来
Hey, kid, come here.
你叫什么
What's your name?
嗨 我叫汤姆·奥福利亚德
Hi. My name's, uh, Tom O'Folliard.
你是比利小子 对吗
And, uh, you're Billy the Kid, ain't you?
是吗
Am I?
我知道你是 我看过你的画像
I know you are. I've seen your picture.
和你一模一样
Looks just like you.
你从哪来
Where are you from?
德克萨斯
Texas.
比利是我的英雄
Billy's my hero.
我走了好远 来加入他的帮派
I come a long way to join his gang.
这是我这一辈子的梦想
It's all I want in my whole life.
我发誓 我不会麻烦你的 让我做什么都行
I won't be no trouble, I swear. I'll do anything you ask me.
恐怕你白跑这么远了
I'm afraid you've made a long journey for nothing.
我已经没有帮派了
I don't have a gang anymore.
而且你来的也不是时候
And you came here at the wrong time.
林肯县现在很危险
It's gettin' real dangerous here in Lincoln.
我不在乎真的
I don't mind, honestly.
-我只想跟着你干  -我在乎
- I just want to be with you. - I mind.
你还小 还是个孩子 我不想看你受伤
You're young. Just a kid. I don't want to see you gettin'hurt.
或者死掉 回家吧
Or killed. Go home.
你父母肯定担心坏了
Your parents must be worried sick about you.
走吧 回去
Go on. Get!
孩子
Kid!
上一次好好吃饭是什么时候
When's the last time you ate properly?
行吧 跟我们来吧
AlI right. Come with us.
吃饱了再上路
We'll get you fed, then you're on your way.
你到底为什么离开家
Why'd you really leave home?
和我说说你家人
Tell me about your family.
我
I, uh...
我不知道我爸是谁
I don't know who my father was.
我妈再婚了
My mother married again.
继父是个酒鬼
My stepfather, he was a...he was a drunk.
很暴力
A real violent man.
打我妈
Attacked my ma.
酒后暴打
You know, in a drunken rage.
把她脑子都打出来了
Beat her brains out.
打得她奄奄一息
Left her dying.
所以 我没有
You see I don't...
我没有家
I don't have a home.
我没有亲人
You know I don't have anyone.
你们不收留我 我只会死在山沟里
You send me away, I'll just die in a ditch.
真的
That's a fact.
其实
You know I'm...
见到你我很开心
I'm so happy I got to meet you.
比利小子
Billy the Kid.
我该走了 我不想
Now I should go. I don't want to...
再浪费你们时间
waste any more of your time.
谢谢招待
Thank you for the food.
别走了 汤姆
You're not going anywhere, Tom.
留在这里吧
We can put you up here.
我教你经营农场 怎么样
I'|I teach you ranching. How does that sound?
真的吗
You serious?
嗯
Yeah.
当然
Sure is.
他说墨西哥人会用
He said the Mexicans would use it.
那是达尔西妮亚 她旁边的是谁
That's Dulcinea. Who's that with her?
查理
Charlie?
听说她订婚了
I heard she's engaged to be married.
威尔逊法官
Judge Wilson?
Judge Wilson...
我 我是亚历山大·麦克斯文
I'm...I'm Alexander McSween.
约翰·汤斯顿的律师
I'm the lawyer working for John Tunstall.
我记得你以前是给墨菲少校干活儿的
I remember you used to work for Major Murphy.
那时我还不知道他集团的真面目
That's before I knew the truth about his organization.
或许你应该观察得再仔细一点
Well, maybe you should have looked more closely.
我知道你很了解
I know you're familiar with what's going on
汤斯顿先生和墨菲浩世公司之间的恩怨
between Mr. Tunstall and Murphy's House.
事实是 我必须在法庭上
Fact is, I'm going to have to fight
与墨菲之家作斗争
House's corrupt practices through the courts
揭露他们的腐败行径 终结这一切
in order to expose and end them.
或许你也清楚
But as you are probably also aware,
林肯县的大部分法院和法官都已被腐蚀
most of the courts and judges in Lincoln are themselves corrupt.
对付墨菲很危险 但我必须这么做
Taking on Murphy was dangerous, but I was compelled to do it.
也正因如此 我的儿子在某个周日晚上
And as a consequence, my son was cut down
倒在了一场枪战中
in a hail of bullets one Sunday evening.
很遗憾
I'm sorry.
我想 你是希望我帮你
But I guess you want me to help you file charges
在法庭上向尚存正义的法官
against the House in courts
起诉浩世
and in front of judges that just might still be honest.
对吗
Is that right?
是的先生 这正是我的想法
Yes, sir. That- - that would be my hope.
那我只能告诉你 麦克斯文先生
Well, all I can tell you, Mr. McSween,
我对圣塔菲圈子恨入骨髓
is that I hate the Rings with every fiber of my being.
在我看来 圣塔菲圈子污染了美国生活的方方面面
It's my belief that the Rings have polluted every aspect of American life.
为什么一群有钱人
How come groups of rich men
能决定对和错
get to decide what's right and what's wrong,
决定谁生谁死
who lives and who dies?
这是对美国的背叛
That's a betrayal of America.
只要还有一口气 我就会抗争到底
And as long as I have breath in my body, I will resist.
我回答了你的问题了吗
Have I answered your question?
是的先生
Yes, sir.
驾 驾
Hyah! Hyah!
你来这里干什么
What the fuck are you doing here?
我想让你不要再为墨菲做事了
I came to ask you if you'd stop working for Murphy.
现在就抽身吧
Just walk away now.
他和魔鬼一样狡猾 杰西
He is as crooked as the devil, Jesse.
那你又是谁
Yeah, and who are you? Huh?
大天使加百列吗 呵
The fucking archangel Gabriel? Yeah.
我是关心你 杰西
Look, I- - I care about you, Jesse.
-是吗    -真的
- Is that right? - I do.
经历了这些 你可能觉得我不在乎你了 但不是这样的
It may not seem that way after everything we've been through, but I do.
谁让你来的 比利
Who told you to come here, Billy?
你的新朋友汤斯顿
Your new friend Tunstall?
你练得怎么样了
How's your practicing coming on?
你还记得我们以前比过一次吗
You remember we did this once before?
-杰西  -是
- Jesse- - Um, it was...
是为了某个女孩
It was about some girl.
记得吗
You remember?
我记得
Yeah, I remember.
我知道你记得
I know you do.
你要开枪打我吗 比利
You gonna shoot me, Billy?
打啊
Go on. Huh?
来啊 比利
Come on, Billy.
你会开枪吗
Would you have?
我想我们永远不会知道答案
I guess we'll never know.
我已经有答案了
I got my answer.
回见 小子
See you later, Kid.
埃德加·华尔兹先生
Edgar Walz, sir.
卡特伦先生
Mr. Catron.
说说吧 林肯县之行如何
So tell me, how was your visit to Lincoln?
非常顺利 先生
It went very well, sir.
我见了浩世的老板 多兰和莱利
I met with the owners of the House, Dolan and Riley
我和他们说了 你对目前
and, um, told them how unhappy
的情况很不满意
you are with the current situation.
银行的事吗
With the bank?
是的先生 尤其对银行不满 尤其是银行
Yes, sir, especially with the bank. Especially with the bank.
他们保证 银行马上就会关门
But they assured me that it will soon be shut down.
-所以  -很好
So...- Good.
很好 肯定不止这些吧
That's good. There must be more.
是的先生 当然
Yes, sir. Of course. Um...
我去了没多久
So shortly after my visit,
多兰就被浩世除掉了
Dolan was removed from the House.
从现在开始 我们只要应付莱利就好
From now on, we only have to deal with Riley.
好 没关系 他就是个打掩护的
Yeah, that's fine. He's just a straw man.
我可爱的女儿怎么样了
How's my lovely daughter?
怎么我好久都见不到她一次
How come I never get to see her? Hmm?
你知道的 先生
You know what it's like, sir.
她 她是个老师
She's a...teacher.
她当然也希望能经常见你
But, um, of course she would like to see more of you.
但抽不出时间
It takes up her time.
对 她压根儿不在意 对吧
Right. She could give a fuck, right?
不是的 先生
No, no, sir.
"No, sir. "
不是的 先生
埃德加 我了解你们所有人
You know, Edgar, I can understand all you people.
我知道莱利和多兰是不择手段的人
I knew that Riley and Dolan were chancers.
我知道墨菲成天喝酒成性
I know that Murphy's fucking sick with drink,
所以我才好心
which is why I choose to keep him in place,
没动他
for sentimental reasons.
但有个人我不理解
There's someone I don't understand- -
这个人让我很感兴趣
someone who really interests me.
我老听人提起他 但我不知道他是谁
I hear his name everywhere, but I have no idea who he is.
也不知道他想要什么
or what he wants.
这人叫 比利小子
I'm talking about the man they call... Billy the Kid.
著名的法外之徒
The famous outlaw?
我对他一无所知 但他却扰得我不得安宁
I know jack shit about him, and already he haunts my dreams.
这人突然出现 似乎要改变一切
Suddenly, someone walks in who seems to change everything.
我满脑子想的都是 他真的是我的敌人吗
And all I'm thinking, is he my real enemy?
我要对付他吗 你懂吗
Do I have to deal with him? You see?
-是的先生  -去搞清楚
Yes, sir. - Find out.
我要知道 这比利小子到底是谁
Find out 'cause I need to know who the hell is Billy the Kid.
我怎样才能接近他
How can I get to him?
孩子
Son.
过来 让我看看你
Come closer. Let me see you.
如果不打算开枪
You never point a gun at anyone
就别拔出来指着别人
unless you mean to use it.
老莫斯
Old Moss?
-你怎么在这里  -我路过
- What are you doin' here? - I just come by to see how
来看看你 比利
you were gettin'on, Billy.
我一直没有忘记你
Ain't never forgotten you.
我们走在山间小道上 仿佛就是昨天
Seems like yesterday, we was on the trail.
你那时还是个孩子
You, just a boy.
-我也没有忘记你  -轻一点
- I ain't never forgotten you either. - Gently.
我欠你一条命
I owe you my life.
你过得怎么样
How are you gettin'by?
就那样吧
Oh, oh, middling. You know.
但我一直在报纸上关注你的消息
But I've been, uh, followin your fortune in the papers.
你似乎终于找了一份体面的工作
Seems you got yourself a good and decent job at last.
嗯 我要
You know, I'm tryin'.
我要让我妈为我骄傲
I tryin' to make my ma proud.
你是能闯出天地的人 比利
You're a survivor, Billy.
我见到你的那一刻 我就知道了
I knew that the moment I saw ya.
记住
Just remember.
事情不会总如你所愿
things don't always turn out the way you want'em to.
等等 莫斯
Wait, Moss.
让我进入你的灵魂
Let me in your soul.